这是二零二四年福建省初中学业水平考试
英语科听力部分。
该部分共三节。
注意，回答听力部分时，请先将答案标在试卷上。
听力部分结束前，你将有两。
两分钟的时间，将你的答案填涂到答题卡上。
现在是听力试音时间，请各考场根据试音情况将音量调到最佳状态。
试音到此结束。
听力考试正式开始，请看听力部分第一节。
第一。
写。
听下面五个句子，从每小题所给的
,B They often play tennis at weekends.
三幅图中选出与句子内容相关的选项，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每个句子后，你都有五秒钟的时间作答和阅读下一小题。
每个。
句子读两遍。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读第一小题的有关内容。
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面七段对话。
从每小题所给的
三个选项中选出正确答案，并标在试卷的相应位置。
听完每段对话后，你都有五秒钟的时间回答有关小题，和五秒钟的时间阅
读下一小题。
每段对话读两遍。
听第一段对话，回答第六小题。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
I'm a member of the chess club.
I have joined the English club and the dance club.
What about you, Jim?
I'm a member of the chess club.
听第二段对话，回答第七小题。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题
is 5 o 'clock now.
Let's leave at 5.30.
Emily, what time shall we leave for Lucy's home?
Her family party starts at 6.30.
It is 5 o now.
Let's leave Hi, Tony.
听第三段对话。
回答第八小题。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
You look stronger.
Do you go to the gym every day?
Not really. My P.E.
teacher advises me to go there twice a week, but I go three times.
Hi, Tony. You look stronger.
Do you go to the gym every day?
Not really. My P.E.
teacher advises me to go there twice a week, but I go three times.
听第四段对话，回答第九小题。
现在你有五秒钟的时间阅读这一小题。
Good evening. Here is my passport.
Thank you. Your flight number is AC -2118.
听第五段对话，回答第十和十。
一题，两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Hello, Maria. The summer holiday is coming.
Where are you going?
I am going to Beijing.
Are you going with your parents?
No, I'm going with Hanmei, my good friend.
What's your plan for traveling?
We will stay there for three days.
We are going to visit Tiananmen Square on the first day, and the Summer Palace on
the second day.
We'll go to the Great Wall on the last day.
Have a good trip.
Thank you, John.
Hello, Maria. The summer holiday is coming.
Where are you going?
I am going to Beijing.
Are you going with your parents?
No, I'm going with Hanmei, my good friend.
What's your plan for traveling?
We will stay there for three days.
We are going to visit Tiananmen Square on the first day, and the Summer Palace on
the second day.
We'll go to the Great Wall on the last day.
Have a good trip.
Thank you, John.
听第六段对话，回答第十二和十三题两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Hi, Lile. What's the matter with you?
Nothing. I just miss my family.
It's almost the Spring Festival.
I'm sorry. I guess you miss your dog and your lucky money.
No. I miss my grandma's cooking.
Oh. You have special dishes for the festival, right?
Yes. We have dumplings, noodles,
tangyuan, and so on.
Wow. Those things sound delicious.
I'd love to try them.
Hey, why don't we make dumplings?
We can invite our friends.
Wonderful. Let's get started.
Hi, Lile. What's the matter with you?
Nothing. I just miss my family.
It's almost the Spring Festival.
I'm sorry. I guess you miss your dog and your lucky money.
No. I miss my grandma's cooking.
Oh. You have special dishes for the festival, right?
Yes. We have dumplings, noodles,
tangyuan, and so on.
Wow. Those things sound delicious.
I'd love to try them.
Hey, why don't we make dumplings?
We can invite our friends.
Wonderful. Let's get started.
听第七段对话，回答第十四和十五题两个小题。
现在你有十秒钟的时间阅读这两个小题。
Leaping, I hear you have made a machine.
Can you tell us something about it?
Well, it is a machine used for washing dishes.
Why did you have such a great idea?
Mom was busy with her work.
I hoped she would have more time to relax.
Your mother must be pleased.
What's your next I want very much to make a machine to water flowers for my dad.
I hope your dream will come true.
Thanks a lot.
Leaping, I hear you have made a machine.
Can you tell us something about it?
Well, it is a machine used for washing dishes.
Why did you have such a great idea?
Mom was busy with her work.
I hoped she would have more time to relax.
Your mother must be pleased.
What's your next plan?
I want very much to make a machine to water flowers for my dad.
I hope your dream will come true.
Thanks a lot.
第二节到此结束。
第三节，听下面短文，根据你所听到的内容，完成以下表格，每空填一词
听短文前，你将有二十秒钟的时间阅读表格内容。
短文读三遍。
Good morning, boys and girls.
Our school sports center is now open.
Come and join us.
The center is open from 4 o to 6 o 'clock in the afternoon on weekdays and open all
day on Sundays.
There is an indoor swimming pool on the first floor.
You can have a swim here.
On the second floor, we have a sports hall for different kinds of ball games, such
as basketball and volleyball.
Most interestingly, you can experience e -sports on the third floor.
You can wear VR glasses to watch videos about exciting matches.
And you can have a ping pong match with a robot.
The coaches here will be glad to help you if you have problems.
Welcome to our center.
Thanks for listening.
Good morning, boys and girls.
Our school sports center is now open.
Come and join us.
The center is open from 4 o 'clock to 6 o in the afternoon on weekdays and open all
day on Sundays.
There is an indoor swimming pool on the first floor.
You can have a swim here.
On the second floor, we have a sports hall for different kinds of ball games, such
as basketball and volleyball.
Most interestingly, you can experience e -sports on the third floor.
You can wear VR glasses to watch videos about exciting matches.
And you can have a ping pong match with a robot.
The coaches here will be glad to help you if you have problems.
Welcome to our center.
Thanks for listening.
Good morning, boys and girls.
Our school sports center is now open.
Come and join us.
The center is open from 4 o to 6 o in the afternoon on weekdays and open all day on
Sundays. Come and join And you can have a ping pong match with a robot.
The coaches here will be glad to help you if you have problems.
Welcome to our center.
Thanks for listening.
The
第三节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将试卷上的答案填涂到答题卡上。